♫ In the not too distant future
♫ Next Sunday AD
♫ There was a guy named Joel
♫ Not too different from you or me
♫ He worked at Gizmotic Institute
♫ Just another face in a red jumpsuit
♫ He did a good job cleaning up the place
♫ But his boss didn't like him
so they shot him into space
♫ We'll send him cheesy movies
♫ The worst we can find
♫ He'll have to sit and watch them all
♫ Then we'll monitor his mind
♫ Now keep in mind, Joel can't control
♫ Where the movies begin or end
♫ Because he used those special parts
♫ To make his robot friends
♫ Robot roll call
♫ Cambot
♫ Gypsy
♫ Tom Servo
♫ Crow
♫ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes
♫ And other science facts
♫ Then repeat to yourself
♫ It's just a show
♫ I should really just relax
♫ For Mystery Science Theater 3,000 ♫
(whirring)
- Oh, Tommy, it looks all thick.
Can we eat it now?
- Patience, crow, proper
aging is essential.
- Hi everybody, welcome
to the satellite of love,
what's that smell?
- Well, Joel, we started
out making a little snack
for today's movie.
- Sounds like a good idea, what is it?
- Fromage, (foreign language).
You know, cheese.
I was just trying to expand
the realm of snacking
when I realized just how vital
cheese is to a sound economy.
And from now on, we're
going to see actual cheese
made right here on the premises.
- Here's the whey.
- Thanks, Gypsy.
- Thanks, girl.
It's not like our other
projects, like when we were
raising veal.
Cheese is less sensitive
to a volatile market.
We're in on the beginning of
a big micro cheesery boom.
- Wow, let's check it out.
(laughter)
Whoa, looks good.
- Of course it's good.
America is leading on cheese.
- What?
- America is leading on cheese.
- Right.
- Now, understand Joel,
this is just a mixing tank.
Now over here is where
the starter is added,
and then of course, it gets
pumped into the curring tank.
That smell you're
experiencing is the enzymes,
the active cultures in cheese.
(pleasant music)
- Oh, this is just great, you guys.
You know, these sneakers are ruined,
I'm gonna have to throw 'em out.
- Geez, Joel, you sound really cheesed.
(laughter)
- Hey.
Don't even start with me.
(coughing)
- Joel, the kids in the hall are calling.
- Frank.
Well, Bezor, let's not waste any time.
You remember we agreed to
a theme for this week's
invention exchange, and that theme was?
- [All] Action figures?
- No, it was action figures.
Tell you what, we'll
make it a competition.
You win and we'll all enjoy Local Hero.
You lose, and you'll be
forced to watch a film
stinkier than your little
pearl's cheese factory,
Monster A-Go-Go.
And Frank here can act as
our impartial judge, 'K?
- You have got to be kidding me.
- We're gonna get burned, Joel.
We're gonna get roasted like nuts.
- Oh, come on, you guys,
Frank's a square fella.
Besides, I think it'll be fun.
Shall we toss a coin, see who goes first?
- I did, we won.
(laughs)
Let 'em have it Steve.
- You know it, Frank.
All action figures have
two things in common.
Merchandising and accessories.
But there's a fatal flaw in
this philosophy that yours truly
and the monkey here have
rooted up like the pussy scab
it is.
- The component factor.
Most kids can't be satisfied
with just a simple startup kit.
One doll naked, alone and afraid.
You gotta have all the accessories.
But why stop with the doll?
Don't you see?
You sell a component doll.
- Introducing Johnny Long
Torso, the doll who is
himself, sold separately.
(blows harmonica)
♫ Johnny Long Torso
♫ The man who comes in pieces
♫ He's long ♫
- Now, you might want to
start with the Long Torso
starter unit, and then
add the action head.
Just look at the detail on this.
- Then accentuate the head
with the right and left
eyeball action packs.
Plus, Johnny's perfect
ears, sold separately.
- Now, get your hero up
off the floor and give him
something to do with
the left arm, right arm,
right leg, left leg, limb packs.
- Then, if you order now, you
also get the high performance
right and left foot upgrades.
All for only $10 with this coupon.
- Not included.
- And then gear up for
high adventure with the
hair kit, the rugged nose option,
the sleek and sassy butt
portions, the realistic
action batch and so much more.
- Now, altogether, this
hunk of rubber would go for
about eight bucks, but sold separately,
one Johnny Long Torso
unit can bring in $300.
- It all adds up to merchandising, profit,
the American way.
- Well, Shmoe?
- Evil, you are evil.
Evil.
- Calm down, honey, it's OK, come on.
Let's show 'em what we got, come on.
I decided that this week my bots have what
it takes to take you on
in the invention exchange
and they've come up with
decidedly unevil line
of affordable, non-violent action figures.
Come on, let's show 'em what we got, guys.
- Well, my figure is called Action Oxford.
It's Edward Deveer, the
17th Earl of Oxford.
Well placed in the court of Elizabeth,
and revered by the
crowned heads of Europe.
Why, it's been well
argued that Action Oxford
was the real author of
Shakespeare's plays and sonnets.
- [Joel] Wow, cool, show
'em all the features.
- Well, he writes, and he's
got a great fencing arm.
Oh, and he embodies that
enigmatic sadness that was
prevalent among late
Renaissance intellectuals and
courtesans, and he costs
only 12 bucks complete.
- Wow, educational, fun,
and historically accurate.
Good job, Tom.
OK, Crow, who's this cool guy over here?
- Oh, he's just the
host organism, but hey,
look in his mouth.
(laughs) Yeah.
Introducing woodscrew tapeworm.
He lives out his life
cycle in the entrails
of the host body until
he's expelled or dies.
- [Tom] Cool, a parasite,
just look at the detail.
- Yeah, the digestive
track's as exciting as the
Amazon jungle.
There's danger, adventure,
and half digested food
around every curve.
- Wow, I want to play
with this one right now.
OK, Gypsy, it's your turn.
Take us over the top, what you got?
- Yeah, well, it's world
champion track sensation
Wilma Rudolph.
She does the 400 meter
hurdles in under 115,
and she's a great role model to boot.
- Wow, now that's cool and inspiring.
Beat that, users, come on,
beat Wilma Rudolph, come on.
- Frank?
- [Frank] We won.
- You lose.
I'm going to spit on you
now, just a little spittle
called Monster A-Go-Go.
- Monster A-Go-Go, Joel.
- And because I'm gloating,
I'm going to stick you
with a short, as well.
It's a flaming little sack
of dog poopie called...
- Circus.
(laughter)
On ice.
- [All] Circus on Ice?
(yelling, beeping)
- Oh.
Hey, you got your circus on my ice.
- You got your ice on my circus.
- Two bad things that go worse together.
- I'd like a slow gin circus.
- I'd like my circus straight up.
- Now you can have both.
- Is this a Max Fleischer cartoon?
- Looks that way.
- Sparling and Darling.
(grandiose music)
- Based on the actual case files of the
Toronto skating club.
- Well, gee, I've seen
him in my nightmares.
- [Voiceover] Step right up
for the newest thing in show
business.
- [Crow] Karaoke.
- [Voiceover] The circus on ice.
Today's glittering ice
carnivals have come a long
way from the annual
masquerades that once wound up
Toronto's skating season.
Yet, still today, they
are the results of months
of practice, as typists and housewives--
- Hey, Bill Abzurg.
- [Voiceover] -- glide
from their work a day world
into the make believe
wonderland of the theater.
- But they're soon
returned to their lives of
quiet desperation.
- [Voiceover] Every branch
of show business is their inspiration.
- Woo, ho, ho.
- [Voiceover] Of the circus,
and no circus is complete
without pink candy floss.
♫ These two girls they make quite a pair
♫ They both come from your worst nightmare
♫ They will haunt your soul forever
♫ And now when you see
pink you're gonna think
♫ We're doomed
♫ They are agents of Satan ♫
- Stop it, Tom.
- [Voiceover] Candy on ice.
That's nice.
- [Crow] Oh, Mamma, you make
it sound so good.
- [Voiceover] Here comes a
herd of performing zebras.
There's probably nothing
quite like them this side
of Africa.
Each one has been trained--
- [All] Ew.
- [Voiceover] --precise
teamwork at the crack
of their driver's whip.
- [Joel] We're getting
into a whole weird area here.
- Yes, it's sexist male fantasies on ice.
(humming)
- Now, this is about when
Donnie and Marie come out.
- Oh, I am not a zebra.
(humming)
- [Voiceover] And now
the little bareback rider
exalts in her victory
over the wild beasts.
- Uh huh.
- [Voiceover] Incidentally,
shows Olympic skating form as she does so.
- I can do that.
- Well, she can do this
because she feels fresh.
(humming)
- This way to the kill floor.
- [Voiceover] In their
galloping finale, the spritely
creatures show their pride
in being the only troop
of trained zebras on ice.
- Yes, it's dehumanized,
objectified circus on ice.
- [Voiceover] --changes as
Jacquelyn DeBeer takes the
spotlight.
- [Crow] Jacquelyn.
- [Voiceover] One of the
world's great figure skaters,
the girl from Paris tells
the story of a fawn's fight
for life.
- What's she doing?
- [Voiceover] The fawn plays
happily in the dim forest without a care.
- Prelude to the afternoon of a murder.
(ominous music)
- You know, you guys,
there's nothing sadder than
a gut shot fawn on ice.
Especially.
- Please, she's an artist,
do not throw pennies at her.
- [Voiceover] Hunters approach.
Frantically, the fawn tries to escape.
- Suddenly, she darts across the highway.
(voices honking and screeching)
- [Voiceover] The hunters
close in, there is no escape.
- Unshaven, stinky, and
boozed up on rumple mints
the hunters spray bullets into the woods.
- Mom, I don't want to
live on the circus on ice,
anymore, I want to go home.
- Shut up and watch the deer
get slaughtered, it's fun.
- Viscera is trailing from her stomach,
the meat will not be good.
- [Crow And Tom] Venison,
venison, venison.
- [Voiceover] They shoot.
- [Tom] They score.
- [Voiceover] Bullet finds its mark.
- Oh, she skates over her own intestines.
- [Voiceover] Demonstrates
the exquisite blend
of brilliant skating and
interpretive dancing,
which won her the world's
championship as she
plays out the last
moments of the dying fawn.
- And now a clown will deliver the eulogy.
- [Voiceover] --always a
spot in a skating carnival
for the little fellow.
- But not in this show.
- [Voiceover] --brave army
of toy soldiers is called out to deal with
the only dragon in captivity.
- Operation Desert Ice Storm.
- The soldiers destroy the
delicate balance of nature.
- [Voiceover] A volley of shots
bravely fired disintegrates
the menace.
- [Joel] Bravely?
The thing was grazing.
- Kill.
- [Voiceover] And now the
spotlight falls on a world
of delicate loveliness--
- [Crow] And kills them.
- [Voiceover] --the ballet,
spinning the substance
that dreams are made of,
the beautiful ballerinas
of the ice create a world
of fairy make believe.
- Yeah, as long as you drop
before you came to the show.
- [Voiceover] Ballet skating
is a comparatively new
development of the art.
It requires all the grace
and control of the dancer,
combined with the rhythmic
sweep of the skater.
- The Emmett Kelly girls do
their famous spotlight routine.
(dramatic music)
- Vomit sprays out in a
beautiful technicolor dream.
- You know, we should
have worn our raincoats.
- Oh, yes.
(coughing)
- The girls with the bruised
legs have to wear the
long dresses.
This little number's named
Always a Bridesmaid, Never a Bride.
- [Voiceover] Individual
artistry is blended into
brilliant choreography--
- [Crow] On Broadway,
but not here.
- [Voiceover] --etches its
delicate patterns on the grassy stage
to interpret a moonlight concerto on ice.
- With a Filbert nut.
- [Voiceover] Every
circus has its acrobats.
- Except this one.
- [Voiceover] --a thrill
a second in their breathtaking routine,
and when it's all done on skates,
these daring young
performers are accomplishing
feats even more difficult
than many an aerialist
in a real circus.
- [Joel] You know, even my mom
would be bored at this.
- Torn between two skaters.
- Yes, it's Jules and Jim on ice.
- [Voiceover] As they perform
their death defying spin,
the girls heads barely miss the ice.
- Women are pulled apart like fresh bread.
(upbeat music)
- [Voiceover] It all adds up
to a split second artistry.
- At the Civic Center, but not here.
- [Voiceover] --of an athlete,
the precision of a juggler,
and the nerve of a test pilot.
- And the boredom of an accordionist.
- [Voiceover] Today's
great skating carnivals are
as sophisticated as bop,
as spectacular as the
beurdoise boogie.
- And as dull as a beige room.
This is like watching paint dry.
- Oh, it's easy when you sit down.
- Girls.
- See if you can spot the
men in this chorus line.
(humming)
- Oh, she's got a sheep's butt.
(horn music, humming)
- Suddenly mitosis takes place.
The DNA strand separates in
a dazzling display of color.
- Hi pro phase.
- Hi, ana phase.
- I'm putting a stop to this.
- [Voiceover] --age of style
in skating, of form,
as well as acrobatics.
- Too bad it isn't the age of talent.
- Wow, really swinging, man.
- Hey, she's got a saggy
type of them leaks.
- Can you imagine if you
were the kind of person
who enjoyed this?
- [Voiceover] The syncopated
rhythm of the dance--
- Is not working tonight.
- [Voiceover] --on skates.
The practice precision
of the Pony Chorus brings
new excitement on steel.
- Yeah, taste my steel.
- [Voiceover] All the color
and pageantry of a stage
revue--
- [Joel] Is missing.
- [Voiceover] Has been brought
from behind the spotlights
into the spotlights of the
modern skating carnival.
- The only conciliation is
that they're all dead now.
- [Voiceover] --choose
four men and women from
every walk of life, who
come together each year,
for the fun of building a newer
and more dazzling spectacle.
As the flashing blades
whirl to a dizzy climax,
the skaters bring to an
end no ordinary circus,
but truly a circus on ice.
- By (foreign language).
- We say goodbye to the
vibrating circus train.
(mumbles gibberish)
(calm music)
- Ah.
(upbeat music)
- I know this.
(humming)
- Oh, I know.
- Wipeout.
(humming)
- Elvis has staggered out of the building.
- It's Billy Pilgrim.
- Wow, that's a new LA club.
- Monster A-Go-Go?
I thought this was gonna
be Monster Go Home, oh.
- You know what guys?
I have a feeling this
is gonna be a tough one.
- No, it might not be too bad.
- No, I think Joel's right,
this one has stinkburger
written all over it.
- Come on, you can't tell
just from the credits.
- No, no, it's a feeling I
have, my gut instincts tell
me this is gonna hurt real bad.
- Joel, it's not healthy to
have such a negative attitude
right out of the gate.
- It's just common sense,
Crow, there's a feeling
of incompetence already in the air.
- Yeah, we might as well face up to it.
- Well, I refuse to give in so soon.
I'm gonna riff away like
it's nobody's business.
I can't think of anything now, but...
- Well.
The other th...
- Jeff Smith, the frugal screenwriter, no
write in for heaven's sake.
♫ So you must go ♫
- Hey, didn't Sheldon
Seymour write the Other Side
of Midnight?
- Hmm.
Hey, what a coincidence,
there are two guys
named Bill Rebane, you know,
because you see with the,
and the guys, this is gonna suck.
- [Voiceover] What you're
about to see may not
even be possible within the narrow limits
of human understanding.
- So let's forget it right now.
- [Voiceover] A space capsule
is rocketed into orbit.
It's mission, to observe new
(humming)
objects circling the Earth.
Satellites, which no nation had launched.
As the capsules reached
its orbit, communications
with it suddenly went silent.
Several days passed.
(humming)
A search team headed by
Colonel Steve Conners--
- [All] Hi, Steve.
- [Voiceover] --intensive
search of the entire area.
- This is Conners, go ahead, Control Two.
- Go ahead, Pump Three.
- [Voiceover] Nothing
in sight except trees.
Coming in, over.
- I'll need some extra jack
sauce and some ketchup.
- Over and out.
- [Voiceover] In a wooded area
(humming)
not far from a space agency
astrophysics laboratory
in Chicago, observers
reported that a strange object
had fallen to Earth.
- A Coke bottle.
- [Voiceover] Patrol Two to
Conners, come in, over.
- OK, now you see that thing?
You push it down all the
way to the floor there.
- [Voiceover] Over.
- [Connors] This is Connors.
Come in, Patrol Two.
- Nag, nag, nag.
(chattering)
- [Voiceover] I'm going
down to have a closer look.
- Hey, good looking, we'll
be back to pick you up later.
- [Voiceover] Was it the space capsule?
- You have five seconds to answer.
- Ding, ding, ding, eh, I'm
sorry, the answer was no.
- Traffic is heavy on the outbound 94,
you might want to take an alternate route.
- How does it look, Jim?
- This is so cool.
- [Voiceover] Wait a minute,
it looks like this is it.
- Take the kazoo out of your mouth.
- [Voiceover] Yeah, that's it, all right.
Looks pretty bad from here.
Setting it down.
- Goodbye, Steve.
(humming, crying)
- I like it.
- It's nice they shot this
film at such a pretty time
of the year, huh?
- Huh, well, I guess this
means the helicopter's landing.
- Yep.
- There it goes, landing.
- I don't know what to say,
Steve, I didn't know you
felt this way.
(chatter)
- We're talking to Charlie Brown's mom.
(groaning)
- He chunked, Steve.
- Captain Connors calling Patrol Two.
Connors calling Patrol Two.
- He's not home right
now, can I take a message?
- Jim, do you read me?
Come in, Patrol Two.
- Wayne, pick up, I know you're there.
- What happened?
- It sounded like he was in trouble.
- No duh.
- We better take a look.
- Take a left by that bush.
- So the government drives stock Chevys?
- I think it's a Bisque.
- Oh, yeah, this is
when NASA was just a car
and a helicopter, right?
- Store in a strip mall.
- Yeah and a vacant lot.
- OK, now, cut that out.
- [Voiceover] Without
question, this was the capsule
that had put Douglas into orbit.
Without question, Douglas was
(laughter)
gone, without a trace.
- Douglas was pear shaped,
very short, and stood the
whole way.
- Ray, look, it's filled
with Schlit's cans.
- Oh, thank goodness Les
Paul is backing them up
on guitar.
- Earl, it's not your break yet.
- The helicopter pilot who
had discovered the capsule
was dead, horribly mangled
in a way no one had ever
seen before.
- [Tom] Oh, quit playing with
his face, Aaron.
(doorbell ringing)
- [Crow] Meanwhile,
in a soap opera, not far away.
- What do you want?
- Oh, Laura, how are you?
- How's Jimmy?
- Oh, he's fine, I just sent
him over to Mrs. Williams.
- Air kiss.
- Have some coffee?
- No, no thanks.
- Yes, please.
- Make it good this time.
- Usually keeps a bunch
of M and Ms in that bowl.
- Oh, feel free to stink
the house up, geez.
- Well, here's the witch's
brew, I mean coffee.
♫ Times like these were
made for Taster's Joy ♫
- It's about Frank, isn't it?
(spitting)
- Ruth, the capsule came back.
- This coffee's warmer than Frank is.
- What about Frank?
- I don't know, he had all
the emergency equipment
he needed, but--
- He was just stupid.
- Well.
- What is it all about?
- Shot was a success, the
capsule did come back--
- But Frank didn't.
- It's just that we don't know whether the
radiation repellent worked or not.
- Oh, I know I shouldn't feel this way.
It's his life, but, well,
ever since Harry died,
Frank's been like a father to Jimmy.
- Harry, wait, slow down.
- Try not to even think
about it right now.
- What am I going to tell Jimmy?
- Who's Jimmy?
- Would you like me to spend the night?
- Oh, you'd like that, wouldn't you?
- I've got to get back to the lab now.
- I don't want to spend
anymore time with this
than I already have.
- There's anything I can do.
- Thank you, Carl.
- Of course we'll be
cutting off the pension,
you understand.
- Hi, Dr. Carl.
- Hi, ya space cadet.
- [Crow] Frank's dead.
- I thought you were
over at Mrs. Williams.
- I had to get some more rocket parts.
When's Uncle Frank coming home?
- You'll have to make due
with Uncle Bob and Uncle Jim
and Uncle Phil and
Uncle Roy and Uncle Tim.
- Burned on reentry, huh?
- --take me fishing.
- [Carl] Well, some trips
are longer than we expected.
- Make other plans, Jimmy.
- What's wrong with Mommy?
- Mommy's not feeling very well.
But suppose you went upstairs
and when we're all through,
we'll have a nice big ice cream soda, huh?
- Now that solves everything.
- Hey, Timmy, my dad's dead
again, can I come over for
dinner?
- Laura, I can't take anymore.
- Oh, look, let's not make
a bigger deal out of this
than it really is.
(phone ringing, yelling)
- Sheesh.
What's that, face like
spinach dip? Horribly mangled?
No dental records? Too bad.
- All right, I'll be right over.
- Well, looks like he
died in a state of sin.
- They've located the camper.
- Two word, closed casket.
- I'll let you know as soon as I find out.
- Wait, Carl, I want to go with you.
- Honey, he'll call if there's any news.
- No, I want to be with you.
(humming)
(whooshing)
- Hey.
- [Crow] Hi.
(humming)
- Hello.
- [Crow] Yes?
- I don't get you.
- [Crow] Oh.
- Are you mad?
- [Crow] No, no.
- Good, because I want
to like you, but I just
don't understand where you're coming from.
- Sure, what's not to get though, Gypsy?
I just am, I hang out.
- Oh, oh, I know, it's
just that, you know,
I don't really get you.
- [Crow] Yeah, OK.
Maybe I can help.
To start with, I'm a
robot, I use cyber based
bubble memory, is that
what's confusing you?
- No.
- [Crow] Is it that I work
off Unix and can use a
variety of operating systems?
- Well, I guess that's a start.
- Well, I've undergone a
complex personal evolution
wherein painful confusion
has given way to what I like
to think of as some degree
of wisdom, culminating
in my current Zarathustrian sense of self,
is that it?
- No.
If that helps you it's good, but--
- Gypsy, I don't know
what, is it that I often
panic while making sandwiches?
- Yeah, well, well, maybe
it's that kind of thing.
- Is it that I smell
conspiracy in everything and I
don't know what I mean most of the time?
- Well, that's perhaps a
small piece of the puzzle,
but I...
- Gypsy, is it an odor?
- No, well, no.
Well, maybe it's Tom I don't get.
- Oh, brother, like a Zippo
lighter without any flint,
I can't believe.
(humming)
- Tom?
- [Tom] Yo.
- I don't get you.
- Nobody does, I'm the wind, baby.
(humming)
(calm music)
- Geez, aren't there
any roads in this town?
- It's a hover Bonneville.
- I think this is the movie
version of Darkness Visible
by William Stylen.
- Wait, I want to come with you.
- No, Ruth, you stay here.
- Geez, you're high maintenance.
- Well, could I have the keys
so I can listen to the radio?
- Yes.
- No, Jim Taylor, the helicopter pilot.
- How did it happen?
- We don't know, sir, we
were having contact with it
from the ground car.
Suddenly, he let out a
yell, and then went blind.
There was nothing we could do.
- You better take a
look at the body, Carl.
- He said garp, then he
said good, and then he died.
- I've never seen anything like it.
He shriveled up like a dried prune.
- Like a drag queen?
- Looks like some kind of
a burn, but it didn't touch
his hair or his clothes.
- But he's horribly mutilated.
- That's what's left of him.
- They shaved his mustache, those animals.
- There's something
else I want to show you.
- Rick, could I get a ride home?
- What do you make of this, Carl?
- Looks like a meadow muffin.
- They look like severe burns.
- What could have caused such burns?
- Mexican food?
- I don't know.
Probably some kid's prank.
- Yeah, kids are always mutilating people.
- Oh, good, now what about the capsule?
- The equipment's on the way now.
- All right, but I want you
to stay here until it arrives.
I don't want anything
disturbed until Dr. Logan
has had a chance to examine it carefully.
- All right, doctor.
- We'd better get back to
the lab, there's nothing
more we can do here.
- Robert Goule and Martin
Milner, they're cops.
- What are we gonna tell Ruth?
- What do you mean, we?
- Can we, Carl?
- What do you mean?
- There's no real proof
that Douglas is dead.
There's no body.
- No bounce.
- Maybe we shouldn't tell her anything.
- Yeah, let's toy with her for a while.
- Nobody hopes for a
miracle more than I, Henry.
- Pope does.
- But there's no sense grabbing at straws.
Even assuming he was blown
clear of the wreckage before
the doctors had ran out.
- You're deep, Terry.
- The wreckage here is
enough to tell the story.
- I'm not convinced.
The condition of that body.
Something's not right.
- We'll probably get the
facts in the laboratory.
- Maybe you're right.
- Hungry?
- Couldn't even afford
to hang the chalkboard.
- Still mad, Evan? Let's talk.
- I thought you went home.
- Too much on my mind.
- You've got a bit of
toilet paper on your shoe.
- I've never been home, either.
Kept thinking about the body.
I've never seen anything like it.
Sure I've been, I'm
trying to find an answer.
- Trying to find a microphone.
- Here I am.
- [Carl] Did you come up
with anything?
- Look, you know enough
about these things.
- Hey, that's my wife.
- This is human tissue.
- Correct.
- But it's different, though.
Never seen anything quite like it.
- I took from Taylor's body.
He was literally cooked to
death in a matter of seconds.
- That sounds delicious.
- Something so charged
with radiated energy...
(mumbles)
- You in front of the
capsule came back with
radioactive energy?
- The capsule didn't kill Taylor.
Here.
- Look, could we get a
miracle here or something?
- Tiny scraps of metal.
Seems normal.
- It is, no radioactivity.
- I don't like you.
- [Carl] --something else.
- Remember the scorch mark
on the ground near the body?
- Yeah, that was fine.
- [Henry] --kill Taylor
stood, or was placed
right where the body was.
Analysis from the grass from that spot,
showed clearly the same
effects upon Taylor's body.
- Henry, I know what
you're driving at, but--
- Shut up.
- [Carl] --but it's
impossible.
Douglas couldn't have survived.
- [Henry] Why not?
The nosecone of the capsule did.
The chute opened.
- I'm aware of that.
(mumbles)
Pass over our radio signal.
- Passover gradient?
(mumbles)
- This fragrant blue bad?
- And why should he be radioactive?
- Washington's radioactive?
(mumbles)
- The road apple?
- Answers to those questions yet.
But my brother and I are working on it.
- He's rather Dr. Bellows-esque.
- [Henry] One, a capsule comes back.
- Want a cat in a bag?
- Two, a man is seared to
death by an unknown force.
- Five.
- No, three, sir.
- [Henry] --amount of
radiation came back with the capsule.
And four--
- [Crow] I'm Perthy
Dove Tonsils.
- The radiation is what bothers me.
- Did you tell Dr. Madding of this?
- No, not yet, and I'd appreciate
it if you wouldn't either.
At least until we have some more evidence.
- Do I need a shave?
- Well, it's entirely up to you, Henry.
Take as much time as you need.
- Bacon as much time...?
- Something else doesn't happen.
- Starting now, go.
- Good night.
- Dear diary, well, you wouldn't
believe who waltzed back
into my life today.
- You know what, this is like the blob.
- No, the thing.
- No, it.
- Maybe them.
- No, it's three coins and a fountain.
Sort of thing.
- So, guess we're through, then.
- --beat the invisible
member of this project?
- Yeah, strange feeling
working three years with
a man you've never met.
- He must be talking
about his agent. (laughs)
- We will return to George
Kennedy and Airport 75.
- Geez, I hate having to drive
my friends to the airport.
Gah.
- Eh, sorry, I broke the ladder.
- Early in 1965, President
Johnson visited Saigon,
he was visited by General Wess Morlin.
- [Voiceover] The episode was
considered important enough
for the civilian head of the
project, Dr. Chris Manning,
to make an emergency visit.
- Hi, Chris.
- Carl.
It isn't often we have such
a short time between visits.
How are you, Connor?
- Fine, thank you, general.
- He's the sky cap, you dope.
- Dr. Shriver, Captain Connors.
(chattering)
- Looking forward to
meeting you for a long time.
- Pleasure's mine, doctor.
- I've been impressed with
some of your theories.
I'd like to discuss them with you one day.
- Over cocktails.
- I'd like that.
- I pulled Chris off of
vacation to come down here
with me.
- And his secretary.
- --told me about the
pilot, I decided it was time
to break security and
bring you two together.
- I would like to examine
the body as soon as possible.
- They should be finished
with the report by now,
we can go to the hospital--
- His face is gone.
- Fine.
- I'll fill you in on the
details on the way over.
- It's a drive by shooting!
- So, beef and barrel?
Barnaby's then, Barnaby's.
Yeah, Barnaby's, that'd be good.
- Hey, General, minus size it, huh?
- Rattle, rattle, clutter,
clutter, boom, boom, boom.
- Weird, it gets quieter
when you close a door.
(voices beat)
- Why, General.
- Oh, they decided to go to Shakey's.
(dance music)
- Hello Laverne.
- Hello Shirl.
- It's the Patty Duke Show.
♫ Rock, rock, rock, rock,
rock and roll high school ♫
- Well there's Lenny Bruce over there.
- Must be dancing at the Slipped Disc.
- A sullen jack hero pulls
on a J in the middle of the
room.
- Chad, the sensitive teen.
- Hey, you put your cigarette
out in my black cow.
- So, this is what goes on
in the teacher's lounge, huh?
- I'll have a little of
this balsamic vinegar here.
Not good really.
(coughs)
- I'm pretty sure this is where
the movie really takes off.
- This is the a-go-go part.
Whoa, he's got an action torso there.
- I'm dancing.
- What is this, the Lloyd Thaxton show?
- Kinda.
Not him, honey, he's got action hips.
- The alpha male dominates the herd.
- Come on back here and fight like a girl.
Come on.
Aw.
- That's a strange car alarm.
- Jango Reinhart tunes up his guitar.
♫ Here in my car, I feel safest as all ♫
- The thin, blue line.
(humming)
- Well, I guess
introductions are in order.
- Yeah.
- [Voiceover] --the delicate
interlocking of fates
that determines life or death?
A series of ifs--
- [Tom] Ands or buts.
- [Voiceover] --if the
girl had danced with her
boyfriend instead of the
other boy, and they had stayed
later, if the two of them
hadn't parked to kiss
and make up.
But that is not what
happened, and fate and history
never deal in ifs.
- I'm hearing your
internal monologue, honey.
(barking)
- He made her bark.
(calm music)
- I have to let that dog out of the trunk.
- It's Creepy the Clown.
(screaming)
(humming)
- Thank goodness my Allstate
man was on the scene.
- Are we awfully fast
or was that a jumpcut?
- He's mangled in another
horrible way I've never
seen before, that guy's creative.
- God.
- [Joel] Jump back,
kiss myself.
- From the looks of him,
General, I'd say the same thing
that happened to the helicopter pilot.
- Could you turn down your reverb, Chris?
- One of the search party.
- Did he see anything?
- No, Doctor, not a thing.
- Ah, you two.
- A nice car, if nobody
wants it, I'll take it.
- Wow, look at all the Butane cans.
(groaning)
- General.
- What was that?
- General, stay with the tour, General.
- Always doing that.
- Tom, Bill, where is everybody?
- Over here, Chris.
- I'm a fugitive from a chain gang.
♫ Jingle bell, jingle
bell, jingle bell rock ♫
- Geez, productive night,
this guy's got 30 bucks
on him.
- Did he just crack her knuckles?
- Hey, look, he can move her
contact around, it's funny.
- She's in shock.
- Good, let's get her
right back to the lab.
- Oh, yes, it's good,
I'll take her to the lab,
my personal lab, just tests.
- She's gonna look great in a petri dish.
- Is he playing her?
- No, Ravi Shamcar is tuning up somewhere.
- I took the grill out, I
think there's room in the trunk
now.
- [Joel] We shoved Mr. Hoffa
over there.
- What is this, Chinese music torture?
- In the southern
provinces, the rice patties
are flooded in the
spring as they have been
for thousands of years.
(twanging)
- Stop it, stop it, stop it, stop it.
Thank you.
- Boy, is it ever a
white day, it must be the
whitest day yet.
- [Voiceover] Dr. Logan,
puzzled by the laboratory
analysis--
- [Joel] Blew up.
- [Voiceover] --made his
own exploratory trip back
to the landing area.
- He's listening to books on tape.
- [Voiceover] His theory
was proved right, and it was
proved right so unexpectedly,
and so violently,
that he'd never live to record it.
- Poor, ridiculous sap.
(birds tweeting)
- Hey, he's good at that,
he should be on Carson.
- You should hear him
do his crested greeb,
really good.
- He brought a bottle of TJ Swan.
- It's Mr. Hobbes takes a vacation.
♫ Butterfly up in the air, he likes to fly
♫ Dog and butterfly ♫
- I'm never gonna find a
plug in for my hairdryer.
- Now there's a man out
standing in his field.
- The young Gramassian
brother scouts locations.
- Now I can take my
clothes off and run around.
- A lone bull human seeks a worthy mate.
- As I mentioned earlier,
there is tremendous
horror out here. Somewhere.
- Dawn on the Serengeti.
(humming)
- How not to be seen.
- Oh, well, this is where
Van Gogh painted his famous
Crows in Corn.
- Crows in Corn?
- Any moment now, unspeakable
horrors, stay with me.
- He's looking for Nolan
Ryan so he can clock
his fastball.
- I see, I think I know
whose woods these are,
no, no, whose woods are
these anyway, no, damn, no.
- Hmm, long skinny turd,
two, three days old.
- Fresh.
- OK, perhaps I was mistaken.
The horror must be in a later scene.
- Now with the Wagner Power
Painter, you can paint
the whole forest in a day.
- Well, I guess nobody cares but me.
(can opens)
- Hey, you got a can of pop?
- Hey, give me some of that.
- Hey, pass that over here.
- I don't have a can of
pop, you know you're not
supposed to bring
anything into the theater.
- What's that then, what do you got?
- Give me sips.
- Come on.
- It's my medicine.
- [Tom] Medicine, come on,
share.
- No.
- Designer Carl Leggefield.
(high pitched squealing)
- Just drop the ball, take the stroke.
- Oh, so this is what
happened to Robert Vesco.
- There, your announcer feels vindicated.
This is extremely horrible.
- No, you don't.
- What, what?
- Well, that didn't make me happy.
- You remember that song?
- What song?
- Would you like to dance?
- No.
- Not without music, that would be wrong.
- You know, Chris, that
dash of gray is very
distinguished.
- Cut the crap, Lorraine,
what do you want,
half my income?
- You'd think we were getting older.
- (laughs) Aren't we?
- Oh, waiter.
- My date is ice cold.
- With two anchovy olives.
- I'm cutting loose tonight.
- Now how did I happen to forget that?
- That's very easy, how
many years has it been?
- You mean since we ordered?
Geez.
- Too flipping many.
- I've got the most peculiar
feeling that something's
terribly wrong.
- Oh, that's the scotch eggs.
- Ever since Frank was
lost, maybe it's nothing,
call it feminine intuition, but--
- Or gas.
- When Carl told me the
capsule had been back,
I almost expected it.
- Barkeep, could you freshen my date?
- And now another death.
I keep telling myself
there's nothing to fear
but I can't quite make myself believe it.
- You two want ham in that omelette?
- [Voiceover] There's a call for you.
- Oh, thank you.
- Oh, an invisible waiter.
- My, he's got a bladder
the size of a juice glass.
- Aha, that's what
she'd like to do to him.
- Stir his olive?
- Yeah.
(slurping, burping)
- Ruth, do you know
where Port Line Road is?
- Near Bourbon Street?
- [Ruth] Mile to the site.
Why?
- [Tom] Where the bathroom is?
- Maybe your intuition was right--
- Well, let's go.
- [Carl] Another strange
accident.
- [Ruth] Oh no.
- Bourbon Street, Bourbon Street.
(calm music)
- Come on, throw it to
me, throw it to, come on,
hey, hey, throw it to me.
- OK, OK, OK, Crow, you know what?
I think Tom and I are all done with it.
Face. (laughs)
(chattering)
- Come on, I'll be your
best friend, come on.
- [Tom] A friend who can't catch?
I don't think so.
- Your limbs don't even work.
- Well, I happen to be propelling the ball
with my hoverskirt, thank you very much.
- [Joel] Here it comes, Tommy.
- [Tom] Alley oop.
Pepper, pepper.
- OK, OK, I don't even want
to play, you know what,
I don't even care, I hate balls.
Do what you want, I
don't care, I don't care.
(chattering)
Ha, I got it.
Hey.
Oh, I'm gonna get in the theater early.
- Hey, Tommy, go long for
the hail Mary, go, go, go,
we got a movie.
(yelling)
(whooshing)
- I got it, I got it, no,
no, it's coming to me,
it's coming to me.
(chattering)
- Hey, here's a Snickers
for being a good sport.
(chattering)
- He looks so peaceful.
- Absolutely unbelievable.
- Called me away from dinner for this?
- He looks worse than the others.
- He started out worse than the others.
- --wasn't anybody
around who saw anything?
- It's New York.
- One of our men recognized Logan's car
on his way to town this morning.
The car was still there when he came back
this afternoon, so he
stopped to investigate.
- Thank you, little white cabby.
- Oh, here comes that boat again.
(humming)
- Snipe, snipe, snipe.
- Comb shack, you out there?
- Oh, haven't you people
done anything since I left?
- What do you think brought him out here?
- Great selection, low prices.
- Must have been a good reason.
- He had the counter with him.
- Great place to die though, real spooky.
- Captain, would you
boys take Logan's body
back to the lab, we'll join you there.
- All right, Doctor, I'll go with you,
they can bring my car later.
- Well, thank you, Pinky.
- We'll just field strip
him and get out of here.
- You have any idea where
Logan was going this morning?
- Well, when we get out of bed--
- Get out of town to pick
up some personal things.
- He was on a wifely errand.
- --any special plans he had.
- Mentioned something about the horror.
- We can find out what
brought him to this particular
place, we might have something to go on.
- Good idea.
- You know, we work good together, Chris.
- I'll just wait here then.
Rot, decompose, rot, decompose, decompose.
- Poor sap.
- Sky can.
- Highest roost.
- Tonight on Wings, the
beach craft bonanza with its
revolutionary V tail.
(gasping, coughing)
- Thank you, Thing.
- Hey, it's Sununo going to get a haircut.
Because he spent a lot of money on planes.
- God darn, Bert.
- --tragedy.
- What do you mean?
- Well, for the last eight
weeks, nothing has happened.
- This is like a totally other movie.
- You speak in riddles, Sahib.
- I thought this was gonna be a lock up.
Thought this was just
leg work when Manning
turned it over to me.
- Leg work?
- Who are these guys?
- --details stuff, trivia.
- There's nothing trivial
about three deaths.
- That's for sure, now I can
understand Chris's concern.
So, let's get with it.
- Well, where do we start?
- He looks like Babe Ruth.
- I'd like to see Dr. Kramer.
- Well, she's probably in her lab.
- She work alone?
- She started with Dr.
Logan, but now she works
with Conrad, his brother.
- Let's go.
- I'm glad we had this
talk, I feel much closer
to you now.
- Well, he's impotent.
And he's impotent, good.
- I'm Chad, from Park Davis.
- Dr. Brent, Dr. Kramer.
- Dr. Moe.
- I'm glad to know you.
- I filled Dr. Brent in on the details,
but let's get to the larger issue.
- Me.
- Did you run a blood count on Taylor?
- Yes we did, actually,
there was no blood.
It all turned to powder, and we think that
counts for the shriveled effect.
- Like shrinky dinks.
- How long was Taylor dead before his body
was found?
- It was just a moment of--
- Doctor?
Doctor, if you could look at this slide.
- We think--
- Doctor, polio vaccine, Dr.
Sock, doctor I think I found--
- Capsule.
- Doctor, if you'd just, oh.
- It's true, we have a
radioactive something or other--
- Thingy.
- Tall, 400 pounds.
- Well, that's a keeper.
- --we sent an astronaut
up, we got him back.
- That's please, it's
definitely the polio vaccine.
Oh forget it, I'll take credit for it.
- That's impossible, with
a perfect two man capsule?
Easy control--
- Ooh, what a gesture.
- Unless I missed my
guess, Douglas is back.
- The monster?
I don't know.
- Apathetic scientists.
- What about this antitium
could be one to be taking
the radiation propellant?
- Yes, we actually gave him
lots more of these injections.
So that he could withstand
all kinds of raids.
- We've been working on
big gobs of neat stuff.
- Well, did Dr. Logan keep a log?
- Certainly.
- May I see it?
- Fine, geez, weird, weird, weird.
- OK, let's see, there's my journal,
this is my coin collection
book, and then my book of
green stamps.
- This is Dr. Logan's log,
you'll find it very correct.
- Let me see here.
Rumple tweezer, the good
fairy lived under the dum dum
tree, what?
- Regular Adelin Wood, isn't he?
- You keep a log?
- Sure.
- May I see it, please?
- Yes, I'll get it.
- Sure, I'll just shelve
my cancer research.
- Hmm.
- Bullwinkle is a--
- Not that lesson, this lesson.
- Ew, mayonnaise.
- Sure is thorough.
- That's why he's here.
- He's thorough, yet gentle.
- Why did you change matidium
50 to 51 six months ago?
- Speaking of tedium.
- --more effective.
- But 50 was very effective,
it was tested on animals.
For a two year period, the
other for only six months.
- I didn't know that, why wasn't I told?
- Listen, I'm feeling a
little picked on here.
- Dr. Logan was so sure
it would be all right.
- Shame based science.
- --doctor, Dr. Logan states
this final injection with
Douglas was 100 CCs.
According to your log, as compared to his,
yours says 200 CCs--
- [Crow] We keep two
sets of books.
- Who's correct, Doctor?
- I am only an assistant
in this laboratory,
I simply work here and I take my orders.
- Dr. Brent didn't mean that.
- Well, yes, I did, actually.
- Security must be upheld.
- Where's Dr. Logan?
- He's either in the
commissary or perhaps he's back
in the other laboratory.
- Oh, let's go see him.
- Perhaps we can have
drinks sometime, hmm?
- Thank you.
- Later, over lunch with Whirley Sean.
- I cross checked your
logs with Dr. Kramer's.
- That's proper, you're
head of the project.
- Well, why wasn't I
informed about the switch
from antedium 50 to 51?
- Because we hate you.
- They're almost identical.
- Well, then, why not call it 50A?
- I said almost identical.
- Or Heinz 57.
- Doctor, antedium 51 can
stand one half times more
radiation.
- You mean the subject can stand more.
- Precisely.
- Hey, this ain't rocket
science, you know?
- --other experiments worked out?
- Perfectly.
- [Tom] Fantastic.
- Six months.
- What would happen with overdose?
- An overdose of anything,
candy with a child,
has a bad effect, if it isn't corrected.
- Where's our pizza?
- I just want to go, let's go.
- --200 CCs instead of
their customary 100 CCs.
Or was that your brother's order?
- No.
- [Joel] It was a joke.
- Dr. Kramer's very
efficient, and very observant.
I did give him an extra 100
CCs for added protection.
That was my reason.
- Did you ever overdose on atimum?
- Oh, I smoked too much rabbit once.
- --absorbed great
quantities of radiation.
- The results please?
- The winner in Los Angeles is...
- So, every one it touches.
- Is that all?
- No.
- Whoever you are.
- To twice its normal size.
My brother developed an antidote.
- My brother's antidote can
beat your brother's antidote.
- The animal died.
- Because of what, Doctor?
- The heart couldn't stand
the violent transition
back to normal.
- And Douglas?
- He's alive out there.
- So, another liney?
- Meanwhile, at Lens Crafters.
- Yeah, bad movies in about an hour.
- Working late, aren't you?
- Don't you start on me, baldy.
- I just have to finish this up.
- I'm sorry, Mr. Galo,
please don't hit my sore ear.
- Geez, you break a
beaker over there? Phew.
- This is fun working
on our projects here,
yet working together.
- What do you think of that Dr. Brent?
- He's a pig, why?
- He's a good man.
Why?
- I don't know.
Really sort of scares me with his acting.
You should be aware of
your responsibilities.
- The hell?
- He's got a job to
do, I wouldn't want it.
- Got any chloroforo carbons over there?
- He's kind of strange, though.
You would think those quiet--
- You're making impostor fragrances.
- Hope it stays that way.
- Yeah.
Now death, monster reports.
- I'm sorry, you say something? Oh.
- I see you've made
another batch of antidotes.
(ringing, screaming)
- Pencils down.
- Here's your brother's last order.
- So, it was a good Martin last night.
What up, I love that part.
- Good God, did you launch a
sulfur bomb back there, huh?
- Hey, I figured it out, he's got his
script taped to the floor.
- Well.
- [Crow] Let's play with
phosphorous.
- That does it.
- Going home?
- Look, I'm working late.
- I do.
- This is what happens
when you get trapped in
an Ian Esko play.
- He's not mad at her anymore.
- It looks like the experiment
was a success. (laughs)
- I don't get it, why is
she changing lab coats?
- Oh, she's got a night
shift at Fermi Lab.
- Damn, she loosened my script.
- Hey, I think you got
page 25 on your shoe.
- I'm gonna snoop in her
sock drawer. (laughs)
(snoring)
- [Voiceover] Dr. Logan
(yelling)
didn't know where the giant was.
In the store room, in that very building.
Logan had learned that
massive does of the antidote
brought about an almost human appearance.
- I did not, quit lying.
- [Voiceover] --unpredictable
side effects that enough
tranquilizer to subdue 10
ordinary men had to be given
each day--
- On an empty stomach.
- [Voiceover] This day,
it was late.
Logan knew that each
passing minute might mean
a return to violence.
♫ Return to violence ♫
He was too late.
- We was too late.
- [Voiceover] Like his brother
the scientist, had an intuitive knowledge
of the situation, plus
an extraordinarily bad
sense of timing.
- Like he laughs when bad
things happen to his friends.
- Oh, that can be embarrassing.
- Oh, look, the musical stairs
from the science museum.
(humming)
- He's sneaking past Robert Frip's room.
(spits)
- Hey, would somebody get the cat off the
Fender roads please?
- From there he looks
like Sketch Henderson.
(whistles)
- Oh, we don't need to see this shot.
(humming)
♫ Time keeps on slipping, slipping ♫
- I guess I didn't have to go.
♫ Oh, what a lucky man he was ♫
(humming)
- I love hanging out after
school, nobody around,
go in the girl's room.
- [Voiceover] Everything
used to make the antidote
was in wreckage by the
time Logan returned.
Any chance that might
have existed, any hope
that sufficient antidote
might be compounded to
have a lasting effect,
all this vanished with one
sweep of the monster's arm.
- Or any hope that the
film would end soon.
- Oh, man, he got my
Compuserve magazine and
Computer Gamer Weekly.
- It might have been nice
to show that scene with
the monster, but use your
imagination, it was true horror.
- Oh, man, I need a smoke,
I'm dying for a cigarette,
I really need a smoke.
- Hello.
- If you'd like to make a call.
- --Laboratory D.
- If you'd like, are you listen, I said,
if you'd like, listen
to me, if you'd like,
oh, can it.
- Put him on.
- Oh, great, I'm dead,
it's the end of the world,
I'm dead.
- I'll be right over.
Yes.
It's urgent.
- The call is coming from
within the laboratory.
- Great, I'm dead.
I'm a dead man, a dead man
and walking and talking
in my clothes, that's
how dead I am, I'm dead.
I'm dead.
- On a dare, I invented
Gainsburgers and I didn't
even mean to.
- Ah, here to borrow more test tubes?
Can't keep your own stock up?
- What do you mean was here?
- I hid him in my radiation lab for weeks.
I've been giving him
injection of antidote.
- Well, it was dumb, Jerr.
- Why weren't we informed?
- Blame it on my state of shock or--
- Blame it on a Bossanova.
- --condition.
I could only think to help him first.
- Kiss that Nobel goodbye.
- --do any good.
- Yes, he became normal, except for size.
- He was huge, but normal.
- Why weren't we informed then?
- I can only think of
logging what I'd witnessed.
- All right, so you logged it,
why didn't you tell us then?
- I don't know, I was trying to help.
- I was just trying to help.
- Help? You've jeopardized
this whole project.
- What the hell do you
want from me, Dr. Brent?
I don't have a precision mind like yours.
- I'm only a scientist.
- But the fact is, Frank Douglas
is gone with the antidote.
- Hey, you came into my lab, you know.
- You're the jerk.
- Huzzah.
- --Dr. Brent.
- Go ahead, spank me.
- We can laugh about it now, buddy.
- We're both a little bit edgy.
I was just thinking one mistake--
- But I can't stay mad at you.
- It's the group.
(humming)
- I'm in love, Jim.
- This is like Vanity
Fair by Sam Peckinpaw.
- Whoa, that guy's got a weird shape.
- No, Crow.
- Now that's science.
- Connect the dots.
- [Tom] Science.
- Hello, ladies, which way to the beach?
- Geez, he's kind of a lumpy fella.
- In all the wrong places.
- Duracell, the copper top battery.
- Hi, I'm from the boys'
camp across the lake,
the backup generator exploded.
(high pitched whistling)
- Is it the Bangles?
- [Joel] The Go-Gos?
- The Lo Quartet?
- Well?
(screaming)
- Libido!
- This is the A-go-go part here.
- No one's going to tell
you you need Clearasol.
- Damn, damn, stupid,
stupid, what was I thinking?
Oh, damn.
- Hey, a whole bottle of see and ski.
- Unbelievable. (laughter)
- General Connors, yes?
- I made that phone noise.
- Where?
(calm music)
- They panicked.
- So you were saying it was my fault?
- --still in shock.
- Was anyone seriously hurt?
- No, thank God.
But he's got to be stopped
before anything else happens.
- Washington called.
- [Joel] He did?
- They put me completely in charge.
Now they want results
and they want them fast.
I need to know some answers.
- Please phrase it in
the form of a question.
- Is there anything else I should know?
- Your fly's open.
- --done all I can.
- [Connors] It's not enough.
- I don't need you busting my butt.
- They want answers, they want 'em now.
Now, don't mince words.
- All right, but understand
this is just a theory.
- But I'm Coco Channel.
- Douglas is much worse.
- And?
- And if my theory is correct,
he gets progressively worse.
- Quit kidding a kidder.
- [Connors] What do you mean?
- Well, when I first hid
him in the other lab,
I gave him an injection
of the antidote my brother
and Nora developed.
- John Lilly called for the prescription.
- And he became almost normal,
but the condition lasted
only five days.
Then--
- [Joel] He left for
the weekend.
- With each following
injection, the effect
of the antidote wore off more rapidly.
- What are you trying to say?
- [Tom] I'm Coco Chanel.
- The last injection was only
effective for a few hours.
- Are you trying to tell me--
- Precisely.
- [Joel] There's your punch.
- --that if he is using the
antidote he escaped with,
as his body needs it,
there is no telling how bad
he will get after each
injection wears off.
- Good read.
- [Tom] That's a wrap.
- No, he doesn't get
larger, the radius of his
danger zone does.
- [Joel] Isn't that always the
way, though?
- [Connors] --doesn't have
any antidote?
- I'm not sure.
But it's conceivable--
- [Crow] Inconceivable!
- --that within 10 hours,
he could contaminate
everything and everybody
within a radius of 50 miles.
- That does it.
He's got--
- [Crow] Sausage burp.
- Alert the entire
division, civilian forces,
anything else that's available.
He's got to be kept
out of populated areas.
- Or it will be bonkers.
- [Connors] --want you with me
every minute.
- [Crow] Yes, sir,
thank you, sir.
♫ John Jacob Jingle Heimer
Schmitt, that's my name, too
♫ Whenever I go out,
the people always shout
♫ There goes John Jacob
Jingle Heimer Schmitt ♫
- That was fun.
Thanks, Kyle.
- [Voiceover] As the giant
became bolder, his whereabouts
were more easily tracked,
and the army was called out
in force because this was, after
all, an American astronaut.
- Oh, right.
- [Voiceover] Official
orders were not to fire.
But one nervous soldier
is all that is ever needed
to start a panic.
- [Crow] Oh, blame it
on the little guy.
(chattering)
- Let me go.
(gunshots)
- [Joel] Lower, aim a
little lower.
♫ Whenever I go out,
the people always shout
♫ There goes John Jacob
Jingle Heimer Schmitt ♫
- So the army's on maneuvers
on Maple Street, huh?
- And in Econoline vans.
- Acceptable losses everybody, come on.
- Hey, they're gonna frag the director.
- Good.
I'm guessing this is a night scene?
Ah, good.
- Yeah, let's see if we can--
- Oh, wait, oh.
(gunshots)
- Huh, something's going on.
- That comes to 12.90, you
want any pop with that?
Hello?
- Johnny Carson.
- Douglas is at the house.
- Your mother's very upset.
- It's like shooting at a wall.
- Not a very big wall.
- Now what, Doctor?
- Well, first, let me finish my tolido.
- I don't know.
- [Crow] What are they doing
at a laundromat?
- Well, he can't get very far.
- The map isn't that big.
We have the entire area surrounded.
We'll have him within an hour.
- Yes, but then what?
- Jackie O?
(engine sputtering)
- Boy, smooth ride, hardly
looks like she's moving.
Oh, she's not.
- Hmm, must be the car.
- Well, the door still works.
- That's good.
- Oh, this is like It Happened One Night,
except it makes me want to kill myself.
- Luckily the Schwans guy came.
- My car broke down.
- Well, call the automobile club.
- Hey, I thought truck
drivers were the gentlemen
of the road.
- Where'd you hear that crap?
- Yeah, well, I'd say
lately, a lot of town here,
let's see.
- I see the front torpedo bays are loaded.
- Can't be a generator,
how'd it stop like?
- I don't know what you mean.
- I mean, did it stop--
- [Crow] Tom Arnold,
road repair.
- Oh, yeah, lady.
- Hey, where you going?
- I'm gonna get you some gas.
- Oh, is that all?
- It's funny, you see, because women
don't know anything about cars.
That's so humor.
- Oh, I just keep an open
can of gas behind the seat.
- Hey, he's putting
ginseng tea in her car.
- Big tea kettle.
- Lady, could you move your--
- I'm gonna watch closely so I
can do this myself next time.
- Would you mind going
and sitting in the car?
You're making me nervous.
- Yes, sir.
- Dear Easy Rider
magazine, I never believed
your stories were true. (laughs)
- Well, she's facing
the wrong way, no wonder
the car's not working.
- Oh.
- Now.
Open up your hood.
- Oh, you'd like that, wouldn't you?
- Can I check the windows for ya?
- The heck, there's a thing wrong with the
whatchamacallit here.
(high pitched whistling)
- There we go.
Move over, lady, I'll start it for ya.
- Because women know nothing about cars.
- Nothing, so it's funny.
- Yeah.
- What'd he do, light the pilot?
- There you are, ma'am.
For God's sake, next time,
drive on a full tank of gas.
- Thank you, Lancelot.
- Shelly's the name, ma'am, Shelly.
- Show him the can, Andy.
- What's this for?
- My way of appreciation.
- Thanks would have been enough, lady.
- Now you wrecked it.
- Driver--
- [Tom] I need love.
- Ma'am?
(groaning)
- She stalls, then kills, black widow.
- Oh, wow, what a smoothie.
- Third time today. (laughs)
New hairstyle's really working. (spits)
(whooshing)
- OK.
Change furnace filters, done.
Jettison dry cleaning, check.
OK, young fresh fellows, I've got the rest
of the afternoon off to
talk about some of the
questions of the universe,
so any question you
might have, ask me, you
have my undivided attention.
- Oh, no, we meant to prepare for this.
- Please, Crow, let's not
make it like last week
when you asked what was the
deal with Jane Pauly's hair, OK?
- OK, not Jane Paul... (whispering)
Well, then, you do it, OK, you do it, you.
- Joel, the Pina Colada song.
- Could you phrase it in
the form of a question?
- OK, Joel, what's the deal
with the Pina Colada song?
Oh, and I have a follow up.
- OK, you mean, if you
like pian coladas, getting
caught in the rain, if
you're not into health food,
and you have half a brain,
if you like making love
at midnight, on the dunes of the--
- That's the one.
- Well, OK, all right, in the early 1980s,
Rupert Holmes wrote the
Pina Colada song because
pina coladas and personal
ads were on the forefronts
of the American
consciousness and, you know,
pop song writers do just
that, they write about
pop culture, you know,
like you know, there's
Ray Stevens, the Streak, Henry
Gross's Junk Food Junkie,
CW McCall's Convoy and others.
- Oh.
- [Tom] Not so fast there,
neon peon, OK, so this
man and woman are in this
relationship for all,
let's say, eight months,
that's the average
national length of a dating
relationship of males 18
to 34, and they don't even
know that each other likes pina coladas?
What, would they always
panic and order Manhattans
or something?
- [Crow] Yeah, and wouldn't
they probably already have
been caught in the rain
together and then one of
them at least mentioned
that they liked getting
caught in the rain?
- And if this couple, we'll
call them Rick and Julie
for the purposes of this argument.
If Julie and Rick have been
together for any amount of time,
well, doesn't each of them
have a responsibility to
communicate to the other
his or her dissatisfaction
with the relationship?
- Yeah, because by responding
to the personals ads,
not only are they cheating on each other,
they're cheating on each
other with each other.
- Yeah, and since 72
percent of the population of
North America lives in a
landlocked state or province,
in actuality, this couple
has no idea whether they
like loving on the dunes on the cape.
- And it's probably one
in a kazillian chance that
Rick and Julie would actually
answer each other's ad.
- Bingo, and although the
song tries to paint a rosy
picture of a relationship
reborn, it is human nature
that neither Rick or Julie,
maybe both, I don't know,
would harbor at least a
fragment of resentment
that the other set out
to cheat on him or her,
which would unleash itself
in fits of passive aggressive
behavior and bitter recrimination.
- OK, listen, all I'm
saying is that Rupert Holmes
wrote a song about a couple
of popular trends, all right?
- It doesn't make the hurt go away.
- We don't blame you, Joel.
- Hey, Rupert Holmes wrote
Timothy, that was about
cannibalism, when was that popular?
- Listen, Crow, it's a well
known fact that Timothy
was a duck.
- Wait a minute, let's review.
- [Crow] A duck?
- Gets hungry as hell, gee
that leg looks swell...
(calm music)
(humming)
Duck, my word.
- In the city?
- Yes sir, he got there in a truck,
the driver had radiation burns.
- How the hell are we
going to find him now?
- Beetle Bailey the motion picture.
- You realize there's over
5,000,000 people in the city?
- And this is one of them.
- --danger zone should be 20 to 25 feet.
- Nora, how long would it
take to mix up 3,000 CCs
of the antidote?
- Not too long.
- [Joel] But I'd need
a blender.
- Do it, and get it to me immediately.
- OK.
- [Tom] But you won't like it.
- We'll need an air gun,
and a tranquilizer dart.
- A string and a picture of Eve Arden.
- We'll track him down with dagger guns.
- That means we'll have to
get within 20 or 25 feet.
- It means you'll have
to get off your butts and
do something.
- He takes one step and
we're in the danger zone.
- Hey, a new angle.
- Wait a minute.
There may be another way.
- Nah, forget it, we
don't have another room.
- --strategic locations,
surrounding the entire area
where the truck driver's body was found.
We could then connect the
counters to a centralized
oscelliscope.
- You know, you look good
without your glasses.
- --exact position, without
endangering any more lives.
- You like Jell-O with
fruit suspending in it?
- Could work.
- Let's try it.
- [All] Nah.
- What would be as ready as
the danger within the hour?
- Reguvic.
- Oh, about 100 feet or more.
- Oh, 100, that's nice, sure.
- It's hard to say.
- Let me say it in a song.
- Wait.
- Dear diary, the general
yelled at me today.
Up, out of time, gotta go more later.
Love, Bunny.
- I can't go on like this.
- Your blood tests came back.
- --antidote at this range.
We better make the first shot count.
- Come on, perk up, Bill.
- I'm fully aware of the consequence.
- Slower, slower.
Oh, slower.
- The cason is making its way past us now.
The rate of this horse float
is made of 10,000 carnations
and clowns are pouring out
of the casket, it's a lovely
sight.
(humming)
- Hey, it's the Good Humor cop.
- Mm, dreamsicles.
- I'm up, I'm up.
- Hmm, so.
So, oh.
- Here comes Roasty and
Toasty, the firemen clowns.
(laughs)
- They're ice fishing. (laughing)
- You know, these cable
guys always come when it's
least convenient.
It's a joke.
- Abbot and Costello in Butt Privates.
(sirens blaring)
- We're getting cable
'cause this movie's so bad.
(laughter)
(yelling)
- [Voiceover] The city of 5,000,000 people
became a huge tomb.
- [Crow] Like St. Paul?
- [Voiceover] The civil defense
units swung into action.
- Refestive gitnies ran
down the streets of vanilla.
- Ah, exact change only.
- [Voiceover] City streets
were cleared of all
but official personnel, with
the realization that even
seeing the monster might
mean that an individual was
close enough to absorb a
lethal dose of radioactivity.
- How ya doing, Steve?
- [Tom] Oh, not bad,
how about you?
- [Crow] Oh, pretty good.
- Right now, join the auto
show at McCormick Place.
- [Voiceover] The long wait began.
- And you're gonna see every minute of it.
- Isaac Hayes is truck turner.
- Thanks, Mom, we'll walk from here.
- Now, I'll be back to pick
you up after fireman practice.
- Whatever.
- [Crow] OK.
♫ Hello, hello, hello, hello ♫
- Watch out for the first draft.
- Bad news, you're not in this scene.
- So, why'd you bring
the leaf blower, Walt?
- Hello, hello, anything going on?
Hello?
- Darkness on the edge of town.
- Cute.
- Hey, Outer Limits is starting.
- Hey, that guy's got an action torso.
- Boy, you know, it sure
doesn't feel like a Tuesday.
- Yeah, it's Dave's birthday,
we're passing the card,
let me finish here.
Year older.
- Huh?
- Oh, looks like the monster
rented a loft apartment.
(high pitched whistling)
- Listen, Billy Pilgrim
has become unstuck in time.
- It's his 12 step program,
(laughs) 'cause it's steps.
- Ladies and gentlemen, KMOJ
Radio presents Bootsie Collins.
- Look, he's got gaut, poor guy.
- What are we supposed to
do if something happens?
Just stand here?
- Ah, take your lunch break.
- Look, look, we're getting something.
- It's Major Dad, look.
- It's only a few blocks from here.
- Better make that call now.
(high pitched whistling)
- Would you cut that out?
- Look, look it's going crazy.
(sirens blaring)
- They finally realized
that the monster had
tickets to see Loggins and
Macina at the Area Crown Theater.
- Oh, they're stopping at the
Billy Goat for a cheeseburger.
- Coke?
- No, Pepsi.
- If I didn't know better, I'd think this
were a security camera.
- All right, three dollars
special event parking.
- OK, back, back, that's
fine, back a little,
that's perfect.
- Lazlo Covacks my butt,
this is great photography.
- Still early, probably a lot
of people coming after church.
♫ There goes John Jacob
Jingle Heimer Schmitt ♫
- Hey, this is so weird, you're here, too.
We're going to Wayne's
after this, are you on?
- Hey.
- Hey, freakin' ripped
off the French Connection
sequence from this movie.
- You know, four movies went
into the making of this film.
- Huh?
(calm music)
- Who's winning?
(chattering)
- Sir, I'm losing him.
- Maybe you should have been
more sensitive to his needs.
- I've lost him, I can't get him anywhere.
- Well, remember why you got together with
him in the first place.
- --Connor right here.
- Mm, cookie. (smacking)
- Anyone know how to read this thing?
- Give me a counter.
- We decided we needed the
help of a housewife and
a balding guy.
- You have a go?
- Ah, go clean your laboratory.
- Geez, flipping scientists
wrecked our thing.
- Yep, my can down, Chicago is.
- Chicago's the windy city, right?
- It's the city by the
lake, city of big shoulders,
or city that works.
- Are you scared, Sarge?
- Of course I'm scared.
Anyone who isn't scared is
either a coward or a liar.
- Every time I aim a whammo
air blaster at a sidewalk,
I get scared.
- Yeah, what about now?
- I'm scared, I'm scared.
- Well, our research
is over, it's pavement.
Time to go home.
- Laverne and Shirley
and the National Guard.
(chattering)
- Sarge, ever worry that
you don't have a face?
(chattering)
- These pants?
- Is there any other way in?
- To your pants?
- The north venture is blocking outside.
- Man, if you can't out act a post.
(laughs)
(humming)
- The Bookmobile is called in.
- Boy, I hope they still
have Curious George.
Riff.
- Oh, here you go, you'll
lose 10 pounds in this suit.
- Ow, ow, watch that, my crack, ouch.
- OK, Major, do you dress
to the right or to the left?
Oh, don't say no right
away, oh, that's so nice,
here, let's belt that up
and see what the final look
will be.
- Pull the helmet off, get it off me.
- This is the most dramatic
asbestos suit scene
I've ever seen.
- Oh, that tickles,
don't touch the armpits.
- OK, now put your arms together in front.
Pull the pants up a bit, there you go.
- Wow, dual overhead dressers.
- Geez, is there anything
else I have to put on?
My brother and I look like
woodticks ready to pop.
(humming)
- Hi, I know.
- Look at me, I'm a Stuart
sandwich with a rifle.
- Don't laugh, here they come, be cool.
- Don't say it, it wasn't my idea.
- [Voiceover] There is one
terrifying word in the world
of nuclear physics.
- [Crow] Oops.
- [Voiceover] Radiation.
As the trail grew hot, so did
the level of contamination.
Here was a problem the
civil defense authorities
had never before faced,
and might never see again.
- How to end this film.
- [Voiceover] --never tested
under actual emergency
conditions--
- [Crow] A tiller.
- [Voiceover] --was brought in.
The mouth of the sewer tunnel
became the center of action.
- Oh, I'm out of here.
(train whistling)
♫ There's a little hotel on the shady rest
♫ At the junction ♫
- Sorry, we should have
had this cleaned before
you got here. (laughs)
- It's not like I'm tasting
my own sweat in this suit,
would you hurry up?
- Would you look, all the
canned peaches you could want.
- [Voiceover] --radiation
is a decontamination spray.
Which reduces the level of radiation--
(sings in foreign language)
- -that were all that man
could use against forces
too large for him to comprehend.
- Tune in tomorrow.
- In the director's cut, they
eliminated the narration.
(humming)
- Come on, dummy.
- If we don't find
Grandma, can we come up?
- Think I should tell
him his zipper's down?
(high pitched whistling)
- Nightmare the Clown, he's
coming to your town, hey.
(laughing)
- Time for your medication, Mr. Taylor.
No, she's not one of
the Germans, Mr. Taylor.
(high pitched whistling)
- So I said to the kid, "Either
get a job or get a haircut,"
no kid's gonna live in my house like that.
- I know what you mean,
what are you gonna do?
- So, lunch?
- OK.
- It's American Gothic on a rampage.
- He's not bad, he's just misunderstood.
- So, what do you want
to do when we're done?
- Let's go to Gino's.
- Hey, how hot is your suit, Bob?
- Sweating BBs.
- [Voiceover] As if a
switch had been turned,
as if an eye had been blinked, as if some
phantom force in the
universe had made a move
eons beyond our comprehension--
- As if we cared.
- [Voiceover] --there was
no trail.
There was no giant, no monster,
no thing called Douglas
to be followed, there
was nothing in the tunnel
but the puzzled men of
courage who suddenly found
themselves alone with
shadows and darkness.
- There was no dignity for
anyone who worked on this film.
- Well, this was a bust,
let's get out of here.
- Come on, let's call the
movie on account of darkness.
- That's a wrap, everyone, strike the set.
- Turned out to be an alien
snipe hunt, go figure.
- This was a test, had
this been an actual movie,
you would have been entertained.
- Phil Silvers tries to flee the set.
- This is a note from
the director, thank you,
everybody, the film is over.
Not everybody will get paid
tonight, you'll have to
check the sheet, OK.
- What the?
- It says, "Sell the house,
sell the car, sell the kids,
"I'm never coming back"?
- [Voiceover] And another descends.
Astronaut Frank Douglas
rescued alive, well,
and of normal size, some 8,000
miles away in a lifeboat.
- Wait a minute.
- Lame.
- [Voiceover] --or how he was
separated from his capsule,
then who, or what, has landed here?
- I thought we covered that.
- [Voiceover] Is it here
yet or has the cosmic switch
been pulled?
- You make the call.
- [Voiceover] Case in
point, the line between
science fiction and science fact--
- And science crap.
- [Voiceover] --microscopically thin.
You have witnessed the line
being shaved even thinner.
- Golly, the joke's on us.
- Boo.
- Oh.
(booing)
- I've got an idea to cheer us up.
OK, I knew this movie
might get ya down, Tom,
so, wala, you're a happy king.
(hums)
- Great little song there,
Joel, real dignified.
I think I'll go throw
myself out an airlock.
- Come back here, Tom, come on.
Every, you know, every kid on Earth dreams
of becoming a happy king.
(hums)
- Yeah, fine, Joel,
whatever, I just rolled off
the turnip truck.
- And Crow T. Robot, by
the power vested in me by
the kingdom of Cookieville,
I know pronounce you
Sir Giggles von Laughs a Lot.
- Joel, I beg you, not
pronounce me Sir Giggles von
Laughs a Lot.
- Your job, Sir Giggles, is
to make sure that King Tom
remains a happy and cheerful king.
(hums, crying)
What's wrong?
- Joel, it's this movie,
it was really depressing.
It was like, it was like
being a little kid and eating
dinner at your Aunt Ruth's
apartment in the suburbs,
and it's hot in there, and
she's got a local Christian
radio station on, and there's
nothing to do or look at,
'cause all she's got in the
apartment are Good Housekeeping
magazines and linen doilies.
- Yeah, and then they send
you out to play with the
strange neighbor kids and
they're all big and their
skin is pink and they
have big pores and a big
eighth grader makes you look
at really upsetting pictures
and so you go back inside
and sit down and they're all
just talking and there are big
pauses in their conversation
and you can hear the
clock ticking on the wall.
- Yeah, yeah, so you dig into
your seat cushion, and you
find a really old peanut, and
you're so bored, you eat it,
and then you just feel
bad and a little sick,
and then you think you're
about to go, but then
Aunt Ruth takes out a photo
album filled with black
and white photos of kids
with squinty eyes and they're
supposed to be your uncle
and aunts or something
and then your parents
force you to look at them.
- OK, OK, come on, come on,
we're tougher than that,
you guys, come on.
Let's think of something
good about the movie.
Come on, Sir Mixalot.
- It's Sir Giggles von Laughs a Lot.
- Sir Giggles von Laughs a Lot.
- Oh.
- [Joel] Come on.
- What?
Oh, you couldn't hear the dialogue.
- All right, now that's a good one.
What about you, King Tom?
- OK, OK, don't tell me.
No one involved with this dung heap
ever went on to do anything else.
- Right, all right, that's
a good thing, you see,
you can throw us any
crummy movie you got and we
can take it, so my
name's not Joel Robinson.
- Yeah, my name's not
Tom, it's King Servo.
- Yeah, and my name's not
Crow T. Sir Giggle von
Laughs a Robot whatever.
- Yeah, and I'm not even Gypsy.
- [All] Yeah.
- That's fine, Joel,
have your petty little
insurrection, just remember
you're trapped in space
dressed like happy kings
and Frank and I are down
here on Earth free to do whatever we want.
- Hey, Dr. F, there's a Matlock marathon
on tonight, you in?
- Push the button, Frank.
(regal music)
(high pitched whistling)